$FRANCISCO\ L\acute{O}PEZ-\ \ \frac{franciscolopezsancho@gmail.com}{(+34)\ -\ 633\ 385\ 837}$ SANCHO ABRAHAM

JAVA DEVELOPER

Profile

Certified Java Software developer

Skills

Development

My specialty is Web Development using Java.

Testing

Ample experience in Testing Driven Development and BDD

Architecture & design

Experience in Development of Software OO, Design Patterns in a SDLC enviroment

Technical Knowledge

Development	Virtualization	Miscelánea
Core Java, Junit	VMWare: Workstation	Selenium,Jmeter
JSF, Spring	VirtualBox	Hudson,Sonar
JPA, EJB	Databases	Maven, Artifactory
Javascript:	SQL Server, Oracle, MySql	Scripting (UNIX and Powershell)
Backbone,Knockout,jQuery	os	Apache Tomcat, Weblogic, Jetty
SOA, Web Services	UNIX (Linux , AIX, OSX)	VBA, Python, PHP
AWS: EC2,S3,Elastic	Windows Server (2003 and 2008)	Joomla
Transcoder,OpsWork		
BPM, ESB		
Subversion, Git		
Ruby on Rails		

Experience

Java Software Developer Argonet Comunicaciones S.L.

02/2012-today

I currently develop an internal web solution for Ministry of Defence. Project is a Web application that allows CRUD of complex tasks and also of its single elements.

Developed is based on JSF2, EJB, JPA and SOAP web services through Test Driven Development. Responsible for implementing migration from a legacy technology to Java, frontend and backend. In a team of four deciding best practices around JSF2. In all area leading Testing Driven Development. Tools used Eclipse, SqlDeveloper, Maven, Hudson, Sonar.

Ruby Software Developer Intec Consultancy Solutions Ltd

03/2013-08/2013

Project is a Web application to manage videos that is aimed to be a platform to upload videos, similar to

youtube. Develop is based on Backbone, Coffescript and Ruby on Rails.. Integration with Facebook, Twitter and Amazon Web Services and Nimbb.

Responsible for implementing migration from a Knockout technology to Backbone in the frontend and refactoring Backend to reduce it to a nutshell composed of API REST Services. Tools used VirtuaBox, Vim, AWS EC2, S3 and OpsWork.

Java Software Developer SoftwareAG Spain

11/2010-02/2012

Project was a Web Application for savings banks to provide capital grant to associations in a national scope. Application will manage this process: capital solicitation, steps until acceptation and track of process itself.

Developed in a BPM, ESB and WS oriented framework.

Responsible for implementing required features, frontend and backend.

Tools used Eclipse, VmWare, SqlDeveloper, Ant.

Java Software Developer SoftwareAG Spain

09/2008-11/2010

Project was a Web Application for savings banks in a national scope to manage personal loans and mortgages. Application will manage this process: loan or mortgages solicitation, steps until acceptation and track of process itself.

Developed in a BPM, ESB and WS oriented framework.

Responsible for implementing required features, frontend and backend.

Tools used Eclipse, VmWare, SqlDeveloper, Ant.

Ruby Software Developer

01/2007-06/2008

Intec. New Technologies consulting

Project was a Web Application aimed to support Entrepreneurs in her bussiness development under "Plan Avanza 2007" of Spanish Government. Application was designed as a table game. Each step will develop skills mostly through a little bit of theory and some question.

Developed using MySql, Ruby on Rails and an Apache Server.

Responsible for implementing required features, frontend and backend.

Tools used TextMate, MySqlWorkbench.

Microsoft Office Trainer

2000-2007

Different companies

Training different packs of Microsoft Office to different clients as OTAN or Airbus

Education

ORACLE CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL

Java SE 6 Programmer

UNED (2011-currently)

Philosophy

Languages

Spanish

Native level

English

High Level, written and spoken

German

Intermediate level